Previously on Reacher...
《神探雷彻》前情提要
Well, whatever your friends were involved in was big enough to get them killed.
不管你朋友卷入的是什么事 其金额都大到害死了他们
There's no way the Tony Swan I recruited is a part of this.
我招募的托尼斯旺 绝对不可能参与此事
Seems Swan's title was assistant director of security.
看来斯旺的职位是安全总监助理
"Shane Langston. Director of Security."
“谢恩兰斯顿 安全总监”
Maybe he's the guy I got on the phone in Atlantic City.
也许在大西洋城 跟我通话的就是这个人
We need to talk to Malcolm Lavoy.
我们得跟马尔科姆拉沃伊谈谈
We'll never get close enough to a senator
我们永远没法接近参议员
to find out what he may or may not know.
从他口中套话
Oh, we don't need to.
我们不需要接近他
Daniel Boyd,
丹尼尔博伊德
Senator Lavoy's legislative director.
拉沃伊参议员的立法主任
Little Wing can knock anything out of the sky.
小翅膀可以击中空中的任何物体
New Age has two bases.
新时代有两个基地
Software made in New York
软件是在纽约开发的
hardware at a manufacturing plant in Denver.
硬件是在丹佛的制造工厂制造的
What are our directives?
我们的指令是什么?
You and Dixon go to Denver.
你和迪克森去丹佛
O'Donnell and I will head down to D.C.
奥唐纳和我会去华盛顿特区
Want to swing by Homeland, see what they know about A.M.
我想去国土安全局 看看他们是否知道AM的事
Saddle up...
给马备好鞍
...'cause we're about to do a whole lot of cowboy shit.
因为我们要去做一大堆牛仔的事
Bye!Quit it!
再见!
Quit it!
别闹了!
I'm gonna get you!
我会抓住你的!
-  No, you're not. - Don't drop my teddy ever again
不 你抓不到的
or I will...  ...at your face.
别再丢我的泰迪熊了 否则我会…你的脸!
Stop it!
住手!
Ooh.
你带肾上腺素笔了吗?
- You got the EpiPens? - Yes, of course.
- 当然带了 - 伍比呢?
- And woobie? - Woobie, Panda-pal
伍比毯、熊猫朋友
Lindsay the Monkey, they're all packed.
猴子林赛 全都装好了
Grab the burner phone.
带上一次性手机
No contact with anyone. Not your parents
别跟任何人联系 不要找你父母
and definitely not your sister.
而且千万别联系你姐姐
She puts everything on Facebook.
她什么都往脸书上发
- I know the drill.
我知道这一套
- Go to Asheville. Take the boys. Plenty for you to do there.
去阿什维尔 带男孩们过去 那里有很多事做
It's touristy. You'll blend in.
那是旅游胜地 你会融入其中
Use cash and this pay-as-you-go credit card.
用现金和现收现付信用卡
Scale of one to ten, how bad is this?
按从一到十打分 情况有多糟?
They're not gonna come after you.
他们不会去找你们的
We're just playing it safe. Belts and suspenders.
我们只是谨慎行事 额外小心
One to ten.
按从一到十打分
For you guys? Four, tops.
对于你们来说 最多四分
How about you?
那你呢?
Well, we're dealing with some pretty bad guys, but...
我们正在处理一些相当坏的家伙
I got the gang with me. We'll be fine.
但我有朋友在身边 我们会没事的
It'll be over in a couple of days, promise.
过几天就结束了
I got to get the baby ready.
我得让孩子做好准备 就像上次一样
Give my tie back!
把我的泰迪熊还给我!
- I need... - She doesn't panic.
我需要你们去…她并不惊慌
Accepts reality on reality's terms.
…去挑你们的衣服 既来之 则安之
Daughter of an ER nurse, Chicago fire chief.
她是急诊室护士 和芝加哥消防队长的女儿
- Tough as they come. - Beautiful, tough, smart.
非常坚强
漂亮、坚强、聪明
She lose a bet?
她打赌输了才嫁给你的?
...dinner. That's what I'm making.
这就是我在做的
If someone asked me back in the day
如果当初有人问我
where I thought you'd wind up
你的结局会是怎样
I'd have predicted a slow death from gonorrhea
我会预测你因为淋病慢慢死去
and a half dozen girlfriends fighting over an '04 Miata.
还会有六个女朋友 为了一辆04年的马自达大打出手
Yeah, well, turns out I didn't want
是啊 原来我并不想要
every girl in the world, just the right one.
世界上的每一个女孩 只想要对的那个
Do you want to calm down a little?
你想稍微冷静一下吗?
Neagley and Dixon just got to the Denver plant.
内格利和迪克森刚到丹佛的工厂
Good. Maybe they get ahold of those missiles
很好 她们也许能拿到那些导弹
and your family won't have to be gone long.
你的家人就不必离开太久
You're a slowpoke.
你真慢
Okay.
好的
A few days wouldn't hurt.You'll never get me.
离开几天没关系
I will.
我会的
科罗拉多州丹佛
The DCMA was here a month ago.
国防合约管理局一个月前来过这里
Yeah, and now we're back.
是啊 现在我们又回来了
We're the cold sores of government oversight.
我们可是政府监管的“疱疹” 总是神出鬼没
Now, if you please? Your foreman?
现在 请把你们的领班叫来
新时代科技 配送仓库
Wait here.
在这里等着
Never ceases to amaze me how far you can get into a place
真是让我惊叹不已 你拿着写字板 表现自然
if you just act like you're supposed to be there and carry a clipboard.
就好像你就应该在那儿一样
- How you feeling?
你觉得怎么样?
Sore.
疼
Well, fighting in heels takes some getting used to.
穿着高跟鞋打架 是需要一段时间适应的
Walking in heels takes some getting used to.
穿高跟鞋走路 也需要一段时间适应
Never wore 'em.
我从来没穿过
- You never wore heels? - Nope.
你之前从来不穿高跟鞋?
不穿
- Not even to a school dance? - Never went to one.
连学校舞会上都不穿?
从没去过
When I wasn't studying or taking care of my dad, I had to work.
我不学习 或者不照顾我爸的时候 我得去工作
Well, bad music, warm punch
也就是糟糕的音乐、温暖的酒水
and some clammy hands feeling you up...
以及一些摸着你的黏糊糊的手
you didn't miss much.
你并没有错过太多
Nobody told me about this.
没人跟我说你们要来检查
Wouldn't be a surprise inspection if we called ahead.
如果我们提前通知就不是突击检查了
Uncle Sam wants to make sure you're using his money wisely.
山姆大叔想确定 你们把钱用在了正道上
So we're here to take a look at Little Wing shoulder-fired launchers
所以我们来看看小翅膀肩扛式发射器
and missiles.The specs, the manufacturing protocols
以及导弹 检查它们的规格和制造协议
the order and delivery schedules...
订单以及交货时间表
Delivery schedule?
交货时间表?
Ten minutes ago. That's the delivery schedule.
交货时间就在十分钟前!
The whole lot just went out the door.
所有货物刚运出去
All 650 of them.
总共650个
- 650? - Here's the paperwork.
650?这是相关文件
If someone had called me first, I'd have held them for you.
如果有人先给我打电话 我本可以推迟交货 给你们留着
- Shit. - Yeah.
- 糟了 - 是啊
Hey, there. You need an extra set of hands?
嘿
你需要帮忙吗?
What I need
我需要的
is your truck.
是你的卡车
爆炸枪弹
We're in business.
一切按计划进行中
匿名来电
Give me good news.
告诉我好消息吧
GPS tracker did the job.
GPS追踪器完成了其使命
Your associates at New Age came through.
你在新时代的同事们还不错
They might be upset I killed the driver, though.
但是我杀了司机 他们可能会伤心
Oh, they won't care so long as they get paid.
只要他们能拿到钱就不会在意
Never underestimate the power of greed.
永远不要低估贪婪的力量
Switch the trailers and get on the road.
- 换车上路吧 - 好的
Will do. Meet you in New York.
我们纽约见
阿扎里马哈茂德
This name, right here...
这里这个名字
...Azhari Mahmoud.
阿扎里马哈茂德
So, the Aaron Miklos we were chasing down in Denver
所以我们在丹佛 追捕的那个阿伦米克洛斯
that was Mahmoud?
就是马哈茂德?
Yeah, we've been calling him "A.M."
是的 我们一直叫他“AM”
Guy's smart. Never been caught, no photos.
这家伙很聪明 从未被捕 也没有照片
Hell, we're not even sure what nationality he is.
我们甚至都不确定他的国籍
From the little bit we know of him
从我们对他仅有的了解来看
he can supposedly pass for Central American
他可以伪装成中美洲人
Italian, Greek, Middle Eastern.
意大利人、希腊人、中东人…
He's a ghost.
他如幽灵一般
We have three short, innocuous recordings of him.
我们有三段他的 简短且无关痛痒的录音
Audio forensics matched it as the same guy.
音频鉴定部证实是同一个人
Each time, he's using a different identity.
他每次都会使用不同的身份
Ideology?
意识形态呢?
No political or religious affiliations.
没有政治或宗教背景
His only god is money
对他而言 唯有金钱才是上帝
and he works for the highest bidder.
他为出价最高的人工作
He hooks up bad actors with the tools they need for bad actions.
他会接洽坏人 为他们提供做坏事所需的工具
First popped up on our radar six years ago.
他在六年前第一次 出现在我们的视线中
Terrorist cell caught trying to acquire tanks of experimental nerve gas.
在恐怖分子试图 获取实验神经毒气罐的时候
We scooped up the whole lot.
我们逮捕了整个团队
All of them except Mahmoud.
所有人 除了马哈茂德
Or whatever his name is.
不管他叫什么
Ghost.
幽灵
This buy was supposed to happen with bearer bonds.
这次购买本来应该用无记名债券
Yeah, financial instrument of choice for tax evaders
是的 逃税者、洗钱者
money launderers and other assorted assholes.
和其他各种混蛋的 首选金融工具
The U.S. Treasury stopped issuing those in the '80s.
美国财政部在80年代 就停止发行这些债券了
Some countries still use them. Those were from Luxembourg.
有些国家仍在使用 那些是卢森堡的
Someone as cautious as A.M. would use bearer bonds.
像AM这么谨慎的人 会使用无记名债券
If issued in large enough amounts
如果发行量足够大
you can carry an untraceable fortune in a briefcase.
你可以用公文包 携带一笔无法追踪的财富
- 65 million worth. - That's the problem.
价值六千五百万 那就是问题所在
You hold a bearer bond, that's like carrying
你带着一张无记名债券
a million dollar bill.
就像带着一百万美元的钞票
The bearer owns it.
它归持有者所有
So no way A.M. lets anyone deliver payment but him.
所以AM不可能 让除他以外的任何人运送酬劳
That's where he's vulnerable.
这就是他的弱点
Just like your brother.
就像你哥哥一样
Back when we worked the case, I asked Joe
当年我们办案的时候 我问了乔
some questions of the financial side of things.
一些财务方面的问题
He said same thing you just did.
他也是你这么说的
A.M. will be the delivery boy. No one else.
运送酬劳的会是AM 不会是其他人
Okay.We showed you ours.
好的 我们给你们 看了我们掌握的信息
Now it's your turn.
现在轮到你们了
We're still piecing it together, but, uh...
我们还在整理中
we give you our word, when this bird's cooked
但我们向你们保证 等时机成熟
- we'll reach out. -  And you have my word
- 我们会联系你们 - 我保证
we won't let this guy slip through our fingers again.
我们不会再让这家伙 逃出我们的手掌心
A.M. and everyone working with him
AM和他的所有同伙
will be prosecuted to the fullest extent of the law.
都将受到法律的最大制裁
Unless we kill them all first.
除非我们先把他们都杀了
Thanks, guys.
谢谢你们
Just like his brother.
跟他哥哥一样
神探雷彻
18-wheelers can't go that fast on these roads.
18轮车在这路上开不快的
We've got a decent shot at catching them.
我们有机会赶上他们
Yeah, especially if they come to a stop.
是啊 尤其是他们中途停车了
Who are these guys?
这些人是谁?
They're the guys who are gonna tell us
会告诉我们卡车坏了的人
the truck broke down and they had to call
而且他们不得不 打电话
another one to come pick up the trailer.
叫另一个人来取车
But no way a second truck got here before us.
但第二辆卡车不可能 在我们之前赶到
- No. - This is a hijacking.
不
这是劫车
Any chance you're wrong?
有没有可能你是错的?
I'm not wrong!
我没错
How the fuck did they know who we are?
他们怎么知道我们是谁?
Foreman must've called New Age about two government inspectors.
领班肯定给新时代打电话 说了两个政府检查员的事
Langston finds out and calls these dickheads.
兰斯顿发现后给这些混蛋打了电话
The fuck?
什么鬼?
- I think we got him. - Yeah.
我觉得我们干掉他了
是啊
Also looks like we got a front tire and gas tank.
看来我们还打中了 一个前胎和一个油箱
- We're not getting out of here. - No.
- 我们离不开了 - 不 我去报警
- I'll call the cops. - Make it anonymous.
匿名报警
Copy that. Do me a favor, grab the manifest.
收到 帮我个忙 拿一下清单
We need the license plate off of it.
我们需要把车牌取下来
Oh, shit.
天啊
What's up, Neagley?
怎么了 内格利?
Hell of a lot, actually. We got to talk fast
其实有很多事
because cops are on the way to a body count
我们得说快点 因为警察 正在赶来统计尸体数量的路上
and we got to put some distance between us and them.
我们得拉开距离
Anything to put you at the scene?
有什么能证明你们在现场的东西吗?
Rental car. It was shot to hell,
租的车 它被射穿了
but it was rented with Dixon's fake ID.
是用迪克森的假身份证租的
We torched it to get rid of prints and DNA.
我们把它烧了 以免留下指纹和DNA
Good. So what happened out there?
很好 所以发生了什么?
- You want the bad news or the worse news? - Surprise us.
你想听坏消息 还是更坏的消息?
让我们大吃一惊吧
Well, a New Age truck with all 650 missiles in it was hijacked.
一辆新时代的卡车 连同其运载的650枚导弹全被劫持了
I hope that's the worse news.
- 希望那是更坏的消息 - 恐怕不能如你所愿
You wish. Tony Swan's alive.
托尼斯旺还活着
- So that's a good thing. - No.
- 所以那是好消息啊 - 不是
It looks like Swan's still working with New Age.
看起来斯旺还在替新时代做事
According to the bill of lading
提货单上显示
Swan personally signed off on the shipment
是斯旺签字授权送货
- before it left the factory.
然后货物才离开工厂的
- So he's in Denver?
那他在丹佛?
No, the paperwork said he authorized it from New York.
文件上显示他是从纽约授权的
So they forged his signature.
所以他们伪造了他的签名?
- It's a digital thumbprint. - Then they forced him.
- 是数字指纹 - 那就是他们强迫了他
New Age New York has iris scanners on the doors,
新时代纽约分部的门上有虹膜扫描仪
thumbprint locks on the computers.
计算机是用的指纹锁
There's no way that anyone could force Tony Swan
任何人都无法强迫托尼斯旺
through that maze of biometrics without causing a huge scene.
通过复杂的生物识别技术 而不引起骚乱
The only way they wouldn't worry about a ruckus
只有一个办法能让他们不担心骚乱
is if all thousand-plus employees
那就是让所有一千多名员工
were in on this thing
全都参与此事
and the odds of a conspiracy
但这么大规模的阴谋的几率…
- that vast are... - Minimal.
微乎其微
I know you want to believe Swan's clean, boss, we all do
我知道你想相信斯旺是清白的 老大 我们都想相信
but things look the way they look.
但就目前的情况看来不是这样
Talk when we're safe, okay?
等我们安全了再聊 好吗?
Reacher?
雷彻?
- Copy that.
收到
So what you said about killing them all...
你之前说要把他们都杀了
...that include Tony Swan?
那包括托尼斯旺吗?
I'm going for a walk.
我要去散步
You boys won't be needing these.
你们不需要这些
Yeah, we're all friends here.
是啊 我们这儿都是朋友
[Franz] Took their guns.
拿走了他们的枪
Long as they didn't find the wire Swan's wearing
只要他们找不到斯旺身上的窃听器
we're five by five.
就一切安好
Like that miscreant said, "We're all friends here."
就像那个恶棍说的
“我们这儿都是朋友”
Let's see what you got, G.I. Joe.
- 我们看看你有什么 美国兵 - 美国兵?
G.I. Joe? More like Mighty Joe Young.
说山地大猩猩更贴切吧
How'd you like to be jammed into a foxhole
你想不想和这个大块头
with this giant motherfucker?
挤在一个散兵坑里?
-  We'll beat whatever price you're paying now.
我们的价格比你们现在付的更优惠
Our supplier can get you all the H you can move
我们的供应商可以从
from an overseas source
无法谈判的海外源头
that's in no position to negotiate terms.
给你们弄来 所有你们可以转运的海洛因
We pass the savings on to you.
我们把省下来的钱都给你们
Okay.
好的
- Let's talk money. - Soon as they agree to a deal, we go.
我们来谈谈价钱
Bust them, lean on them
他们一达成协议 我们就出动
they give up their source; we bust them
逮捕他们 逼迫他们 他们会说出他们的货源
then we all get bumped.
我们逮捕他们 然后全都能升职
More fruit salad on our chests...
胸前的绶带和奖章就更多了
More dollar signs on our paychecks, bro.
薪水支票上还会有 更多美元标志哦 兄弟
Why would they add dollar signs to our paychecks?
为什么要在我们的薪水支票上 加美元标志?
- Shut up, Franzy. - The kid's got a point, Manuel.
闭嘴 弗朗茨
You only need one dollar sign.
这孩子说得有道理 曼努埃尔 一个美元标志就够了 重点是零
- Assholes. - Heads up.We got incoming.
混蛋 小心 有人靠近
About time.
早该来了
110?
You said you could beat our current price.
你之前说价格会优于我们目前的价格
- I am beating it.
我给你们优惠了啊
- Not by enough.
还不够
You want us to change suppliers, motivate us.
你想让我们更换供应商 那就打动我们吧
This is chicken. I said pork.
鸡肉?我说的是猪肉
- You heard me order it. - Okay.
你听到我说的了。-好吧
Fucking idiots always get it wrong.
白痴总是搞错
How's 105?
105怎么样?
Sounds like you're wasting my fucking time.
听起来像是在浪费我的时间
- You got forks? -  You have another brick
你还找得到这么纯卖105的吗?
- as pure as that for 105? - Seen better.
- 我见过更好的 - 胡说
Bullshit. I got a list of other buyers
我有一长串买家的名单
- a mile long. I came to you... - I know you.
- 我来找你是因为你的量… - 我认识你
...because you purchase at a volume
- …值得我花时间协商
- which makes it worthwhile. - I don't think so.
- 你认错人了吧
Yeah, I do.
没认错
Where do I know you from?
我从哪儿认识你的来着?
- Hold on.
糟了 等等
- Might be nothing. - No idea.
- 可能没什么 -不知道
-  Look, I have other offers coming in. - I know we've met before.
- 我知道我们以前见过
What can you do for me?
- 你能为我做什么?
100. Take it or leave it.
- 一百 要么接受 要么就算了
I got it. You're the guy I sold my guitar to a while back.
你是前不久买我吉他的那个人
You got me mixed up with somebody else.
你把我跟其他人搞混了
Craigslist, dude.
克雷格列表网 兄弟
You bought my acoustic.
你买了我的原声吉他
We gonna eat and discuss old times
我们是要吃饭叙旧
or are we gonna make a deal?
还是达成协议?
You assholes don't want this stuff
你们这些混蛋不想要这些东西
we got other places we can sell it.
我们有其他地方可以卖
Wait a minute.
等等
Wait a minute, when this guy bought it
等等 这家伙买吉他的时候
he was in an Army cop uniform.
他穿着宪兵的制服
Fuck.
妈的
- Go, go, go, go.
上!
Look out!
小心!
- Call an ambulance! - Don't shoot!
- 叫救护车! - 别开枪
- We have an officer down.
我们有一名军官倒下了 需要医疗救援
- We need medical assistance. - The bullet missed your heart.
- 子弹没打中你的心脏
But shattered my collarbone.
- 但打碎了我的锁骨
Not gonna be playing that guitar for a while.
我有段时间弹不了吉他了
- Every cloud...  Fuck you.
塞翁失马
去你的
- Hey, who don't you mess with? - The Teamsters?
嘿 你不能招惹谁?
卡车驾驶员工会?
I owe you one.
我欠你一个人情
Let me guess.
让我猜猜
Government plates, government suits
政府牌照、政府制服
government rides.
政府的车
Surprised it took Senator Lavoy this long
没想到拉沃伊议员花了这么长时间
to figure out who sweated his flunky last night.
才查出昨晚是谁动了他的走狗
The senator has a proposition for you. Get in.
参议员有个提议给你 上车
No.
不
- Why not, Mr. Reacher?
为什么 雷彻先生?
- Just "Reacher."
叫我雷彻
Fine, Reacher. Why won't you get in the car?
好吧 雷彻 你为什么不上车?
Because he didn't ask nicely.
因为他语气不善
Okay.
好的
Hart, what's the magic word?
哈特 那个神奇的词是什么?
Please get in the vehicle?
请你上车?
My man in Denver barely got away with the merchandise.
我在丹佛的人带着货物侥幸逃脱
I'm paying a premium for a seamless transaction
我为了实现无缝交易 付出了额外的代价
and so far this has been anything but seamless.
而且目前为止 这已经算不上是无缝交易了
If these problems persist
如果这些问题持续存在
there may have to be a price adjustment.
那可能得调整价格了
Some of Mr. Swan's old friends are causing us problems
斯旺先生的一些老朋友 给我们带来了麻烦
but it's nothing we can't handle.
但没什么是我们处理不了的
If you want the merchandise, you honor the deal.
如果你想要商品 就得遵守交易
Do what you promised and I will.
做你答应做的事 而我也会如此
Okay. Good.
好的
很好
Where are you now?
你现在在哪里?
I am just outside...
我就在外面
Oh, no, t-this can't be right.
不 这不可能是真的吧
"French Lick"?
“弗伦奇利克”
- Fucking Americans. - Indiana.
他妈的美国人 印第安纳州
Okay.
好的
The Little Wing chips will be ready to install
等你到达这里时 小翅膀的芯片
in the missiles by the time you get here.
会准备好安装在导弹里
And Mr. Swan's associates will be taken care of.
斯旺先生的同事们也会处理好的
- That plan's already in motion.
计划已经开始实施了
Fuck your king. Prick.
去他妈的英国佬
蠢货
华盛顿特区史密森国家动物园
Backstage at the primate exhibit?
在灵长类动物展示区的后面
Dramatic.
够夸张的
Thought you might feel comfortable among the gorillas.
我以为你们在大猩猩中间会很舒服
Mr. Reacher, I'm Malcolm Lavoy.
雷彻先生 我是马尔科姆拉沃伊
- He prefers just "Reacher." - No.
- 他更喜欢你叫他“雷彻” - 不
He has to call me "Mister."
他必须叫我“先生”
My apologies for the manner in which
雷彻先生 很抱歉我让人
you were brought in here, Mr. Reacher.
用这种方式把你带过来
Assume you use this location 'cause it's one
我猜你使用这个地方 是因为这是华盛顿特区为数不多的
of the few spots in D.C. where you can meet
你可以在没有人监视
without prying eyes or surveillance bugs.
或窥探的情况下见面的地方
Mm-hmm. It's why I got myself appointed to the zoo's board.
这就是为什么我任命 自己为动物园董事会成员
- Ah, I believe you know
我相信你认识
my legislative director, Mr. Boyd.
我的立法主任 博伊德先生吧?
Yeah, he's the one who likes cocaine.
是的
就是他喜欢可卡因
You know, when I found out what happened
我知道发生了什么后
I reached out to a friend of mine at the Bureau.
我联系了我在局里的一个朋友
Imagine Boyd's embarrassment when he learned
想象一下博伊德知道
that the people he revealed our secrets to
自己一开始把我们的秘密透露给了
weren't FBI agents in the first place.
非联邦特工有多尴尬
Security video showed you entering the precinct
监控录像显示你们进入了辖区
and facial recognition software matched you to a military ID.
面部识别软件 将你和一个军人的身份证相匹配
Jack Reacher. No middle name.
杰克雷彻
West Point, two Silver Stars
没有中间名 西点军校出身 两枚银星
a Bronze Star, Purple Heart and so on.
一枚铜星、一枚紫心勋章等等
Show some respect.
放尊重点
That is quite a list, and I want to thank you
很多勋章啊 顺便说一句
for your service, by the way.
感谢你的服役
Seems like after you retired
你退役后
you kind of fell off the face of the Earth.
像是从人间蒸发了一样
Except for this incident a couple years ago
除了几年前 在佐治亚州马格雷夫
in Margrave, Georgia.
的一起事件
Charged with the murder of your own brother.
你被指控杀了自己的兄弟
You were, of course, exonerated.
你当然被无罪释放了
Then a massive counterfeiting operation
然后 乔之前一直在调查的
that Joe had been investigating
一个大规模伪造行动
literally and figuratively burned to the ground.
实实在在地被烧毁了
Now, the official story was
现在 官方的说辞是
that it was all the work of a rookie cop
那都是一个菜鸟警察
and an out-of-town veteran.
和一个外地退伍军人干的
The same out-of-town veteran
也就是在波士顿逮捕了
that arrested Boyd here in Boston.
博伊德的这位外地退伍军人
Get to the point.
说重点吧
Smells like monkey shit in here.
这里有股猴子屎的味道
Well, I know it was you in Margrave, Mr. Reacher.
雷彻先生 我知道马格雷夫的事 是你做的
I want you to do the same thing for the situation we have here.
我希望针对我们目前的情况 你也能做同样的事
- Why? - Because in Boston, you insinuated to Boyd
为什么?
因为在波士顿 你暗示博伊德
that military and civilian aircraft
军队和民用飞机
could be in danger due to Little Wing.
可能会因为小翅膀而陷入危险
Now, I can only assume that means that terrorists
现在 我只能假设那意味着
恐怖分子对这项技术很感兴趣
are interested in the tech, working hard to obtain it.
正在努力获得它
See, once we identified you, we looked into things deeper
一旦我们确认了你的身份 我们就深入调查
and we learned that your old unit's back together
我们知道你以前的小队又重组了
and some are dead.
其中有些人死了
Don't look so shocked, Mr. Reacher
别那么震惊 雷彻先生
I'm a U.S. congressman, I get things done.
我是美国国会议员 我能把事情做好
I'm shocked because a U.S. congressman got anything done.
我很震惊 是因为 美国国会议员居然还能做事
I'm used to the slings and arrows, Mr. Reacher.
我已经习惯了 人们的阴阳怪气 雷彻先生
But bottom line the people who want this weaponry
我的底线是想要这个武器的人
can never be allowed to have it.
绝对不能被允许持有该武器
Because if anyone knew
因为如果有人知道
you were involved in the shady dealings
你从一开始就参与了
that created Little Wing in the first place
创造小翅膀的不正当交易
you'd be indicted.
你就会被起诉
Get rid of the bad guys, keep my hands clean.
除掉坏人 让我干干净净的
In Washington, we call that a win-win.
在华盛顿 我们称之为双赢
I did what I did to give our side the tools they need
我尽我所能 给予了我方捍卫民主
to defend democracy.
所需的工具
I just avoided the typical red tape that does nothing
我只是避免了繁文缛节 那些没什么用 只会拖延时间
but cause the delays that cost lives.
造成生命损失
And lined your pockets in the process.
还在这个过程中中饱私囊
Again, win-win.
再次重申 这叫双赢
But I don't want innocent people to die because of it.
我不想让无辜群众因为这种武器而死
I'm a political animal, I'm not a monster, Mr. Reacher.
我是政客 不是怪物 雷彻先生
And I'm not asking for your help
而且我不是请你帮忙
I'm offering you mine.
我是给你提供帮助
You're the kind of man who likes to gets things done, too.
你也是那种喜欢把事情做好的人
Your record in the military, and in Margrave, proves that.
你在军队和马格雷夫的记录 证明了这一点
You like to upset the apple cart.
你喜欢打乱计划
Well, I'm prepared to give you whatever you need
我准备给予你所需要的一切
to aid you in that endeavor.
协助你完成这项任务
And when you're done
等你完工后
no one will be able to prove that you were ever near
没有人能证明你
those apples in the first place.
曾卷入过那些计划
Just smash this thing to bits. Leave no man left standing.
就把这些东西砸成碎片 把这些人全都一网打尽
No one left to endanger lives.
不遗留任何人威胁他人生命
And then you can disappear again.
然后你就又可以消失了
No one will go looking for you.
没有人会继续找你
Or your friends.
我们是你的朋友
Yeah?
怎么?
Hey, Not-So-Jolly Green Giant.
嘿 不怎么快乐的巨人
- You throw away that suit yet? - No. Why?
你已经把那套衣服扔了吗?
Coroner finally released Franz's body.
没有 怎么了?
验尸官终于归还了弗朗茨的尸体
Funeral's tomorrow.
葬礼在明天举行
We got to go back to New York.
我们得回纽约
Had my office make some discrete inquiries.
葬礼
Denver sheriffs found the shot-up truck
我让我的办公室做了一些零星的调查
with a switched-out trailer.Nothing in it but crates of bricks.
丹佛的警察发现了 被枪击的卡车和被掉包的拖车
Guessing they perfectly matched the weight
- 里面什么都没有 只有几块砖 - 它们完美匹配
of the launchers and the missiles.
发射器和导弹的重量?
Yep. It seems their plan
是的 看来他们的计划 是开车将假的货物
was to drive the dummy cargo down to the port
运送到洛杉矶港口
- in L.A. - And ship it to an Army base
然后送到菲律宾的军事基地
in the Philippines or wherever the weapons were supposed to go.
或者任何那武器应该去的地方
South Korea, according to the documents we saw.
根据我们的资料显示 是韩国
Smart.
真聪明
Three to four weeks for a cargo ship to get there
货船从西海岸到那里 需要三到四周的时间
from the West Coast, no one knows the weapons were missing
在另一边开箱前
till they open it up on the other end.
没人知道武器失踪了
And who knows how long that could be?
谁知道那要多长时间呢?
Army could just load it into storage
军队可能会直接将其放到仓库
and not see them again for months.
几个月都不看它们
And by then, it's too late.
到那时 为时已晚
Terrorists have taken down dozens of planes
恐怖分子已经击落了数十架飞机
and we have no idea where they got the firepower.
而我们还不知道 他们从哪儿弄来的武器
Speaking of firepower, we have any leads
说起武器
as to where the real missiles went?Colorado State Police found the truck
有任何关于真正的导弹的 去向的线索吗?
in a field outside Denver.- It was empty.
科罗拉多州警方在丹佛外的 一块田里发现了那辆卡车 是空的
- Based on the tracks in the dirt
根据卡车在泥土里的痕迹来看
they think a private plane flew the weapons out overnight.
他们认为一架私人飞机 连夜把武器带走了
Could be headed here.
它可能会去往任何地方
Since 9/11, they've kept a pretty close watch on New York's skies.
自从911以后 纽约上空就一直受到了密切地监控
And we know A.M.'s cautious.
我们知道AM很谨慎
I were him, I'd fly them into some small airstrip
如果我是他
我会把它们带到 宾夕法尼亚州的某个小机场里
in Pennsylvania, maybe New Hampshire
也可以是新罕布什尔州 再开车将武器运到纽约
then drive the weapons into New York to load them up
好给它们加上小翅膀软件
- with the Little Wing software. - That makes sense.
言之有理
We need to know exactly where the missiles are headed
我们需要知道导弹 到底是在往哪儿运
so we can intercept them.
才能拦截它们
'Cause when the money changes hands
因为当钱易手时
A.M. will be there, and so will the people who killed our guys.
AM会到场 杀了我们的人的凶手也在
Reacher. You seeing this shit?
雷彻 你看到那玩意了吗?
Isn't that that toy he had in his car the other day?
那不是那天他车里的玩具吗?
Mikey.My nephews have the same one.
米奇 我的侄子也有一个
It's a great toy.
这是个很棒的玩具
We play with it all the time.
我们一直一起玩
When I was a kid, I had Aquaman.
我小时候 我有海王
I thought it was so cool how he could talk to fish.
我觉得他跟鱼说话的方式太酷了
'Cause I wanted to talk to my dog, you know?
因为我当时也想跟我的狗说话
Hey.
嘿
I want you to have this, too.
我也想把这张照片给你 这是我的
This was mine. Saint Jerome.
圣杰罗姆
He's the patron saint of kids
他是爸爸或妈妈去了天堂的
whose moms and dads go to heaven.
孩子的守护神
I want you to say the prayer...on the back every night.
我希望你每晚都念这照片后面的祈祷词
It'll help keep your dad close.
它会让你爸离你近点
Can you do that?
你能做到吗?
Good boy.
好孩子
You need anything, you call me.
你有任何需要 就给我打电话
Day or night.
白天晚上都行
- Thank you. - Yeah.
- 谢谢 - 没事
Come on, Mikey. They're just about to start.
来吧 米奇 葬礼要开始了
Why are you giving toys to my dead friend's son?
你为什么要送玩具 给我死去的朋友的儿子?
Excuse me?
什么?
Cozy up to the kid, score points with Mom.
和孩子相处融洽 就能刷妈妈的好感度
You see a grieving widow and think, "Easy target"?
你看到一个悲伤的寡妇 心想：“这个目标容易得手”?
Are you kidding me right now?
你现在在跟我开玩笑吗?
You got some kind of death wish?
你是想找死吗?
- Some people think so. - I'm here to pay my respects.
有些人这么想
我是来表达敬意的
Why did a biker gang take a run at me in Boston last night?
为什么昨晚在波士顿 有一个摩托车团伙攻击我?
- 'Cause you're an asshole. - Possibly.
因为你是个混蛋 可能吧
Or maybe it's 'cause you're the only person I told
也可能是因为 我们只把
- we were going there. - Wait, wait, wait.
我们的行踪告诉了你 等等
Are you trying to say that I'm bent?
你是想说我是黑警?
Not trying to say anything.
我什么都没想说
You know why I was talking to Mikey?
你知道我为什么跟米奇说话吗?
Because I know what he's going through.
因为我知道他在经历什么
I know what it is to look out the window every night
我知道每晚看着窗户外面
and pray that the next set of headlights coming down the street is your father's car
祈祷街上来的是自己父亲的车 是什么感觉
even though you know it'll never happen
即使你知道那永远不会发生
because you saw the guys from Romano's funeral home
因为你亲眼看到 罗马诺殡仪馆的那些家伙
throw dirt on his casket.
在他的棺材上撒土
Do you know what it is to lose family?
你知道失去家人是什么感觉吗?
Yeah, they're all dead. Every one of them.
是啊 他们都死了 全都死了
And I was talking about you, not your father.
而我在说你 - 没说你爸
I'm talking about him.
- 我在说他
My father was a cop, a good one
我爸曾是一名警察 一个好警察
and he refused to be on the take and they killed him for it.
他拒绝受贿 因此被人杀害
Look, I know that's your friend's son and widow.
听着 我知道那是 你朋友的儿子和遗孀
I get it.
我懂
But you call me dirty one more time
但如果你再说我是黑警
and I don't care if we're standing in front of the statue of the Holy Mother
我不在乎我们是否是站在圣母像面前
I will give you that beating that I owe you right here.
我会新账老账一起算 就在这里狠狠揍你一顿
One, I'll take that fight any time you want.
第一 只要你想 我随时奉陪
And two...
第二
I didn't know that about your father.
我不知道你父亲的事
Yeah, well, what you don't know could fill the Javits.
是啊 你不知道的事可多了去了
Because while you were in Boston doing God knows what
因为天知道你在波士顿做什么的时候
I was running those security names from New Age.
我在忙着查新时代安保部的人
All former NYPD, all from the 3rd precinct.
他们全都是前纽约市警察局的
The boss, Langston and a few other guys
全部来自第三分局
they were under investigation by IA.
老板兰斯顿和其他几个人 都接受过内务部的调查
They took early retirement and the charges went away.
他们提前退休了 那些指控就消失了
Then they all got cushy jobs at New Age
然后他们全都在新时代 找到了轻松的工作
and they hired all their pals along.
雇佣了所有朋友
Whole team of bad cops?
整个团队全是黑警?
Everybody except your buddy Swan.
所有人 除了你的朋友 斯旺
But he's the only one that has military experience
但他是唯一一个有从军经历
to know what type of weapons terrorists want, so...
知道恐怖分子 想要哪种武器的人 所以…
Now you're implying something that's pissing me off.
现在你在含沙射影地说 会让我生气的事
You can't deny he makes sense for this.
你不能否认这种猜想是合理的
With his background, for all we know
根据他的背景
he might have put the whole thing together.
这一切可能都是他主使的
All cops, all bad, all from the same precinct.
所有警察 全是黑警 都是一个辖区的
- You interview any of them? - Couldn't.
- 你审问过他们中任何人吗? - 问不了
You turned their office into a drive-through.
你在他们办公的地方砸出了一个大洞
They went to the ground.
他们躲起来了
Their places were empty, just like Tony Swan's.
他们的住处空无一人 跟托尼斯旺的住处一样
You want to call somebody dirty?
你想骂某人是黑警?
First look in your own backyard.
先查查你自己的后院吧
We therefore commit our brother Calvin Franz to the ground
因此 我们要将我们的兄弟 卡尔文弗朗茨埋葬
earth to earth, ashes to ashes, dust to dust
归于大地 尘归尘 土归土
in sure and certain hope of the resurrection
让往生者安宁
to the eternal life.
让在世者重获解脱
Amen.
阿门
Firing party, attention.
鸣枪队 注意!
Stand by.
待命
Ready.
准备
Aim.
瞄准
Fire.
开火!
Ready.
准备
Aim.- Fire.
瞄准 开火!
- Get down! - Fire...
- 趴下! - 开火
I got you. Come on. Let's go.
我保护你们 快 我们走
Get out of here. Go.
离开这里 快走!
Active shooters! Run!
有人开枪 快跑!
Go!
走!
How many?
- 几个人?
As far as I can tell, two. Across the road.
- 据我所知两个 在路对面
Handguns are useless from this distance. We got to get closer.
- 手枪没用 得离近点!
Flank them. Neagley and I will take the one on the right.
包抄他们 内格利和我 负责右边的那个
You two take the one on the left.
你们俩负责左边那个
Go.
上
Close as we're gonna get. It's not enough.
我们尽可能接近 还不够
- We could wait for the cops. - We can't let them get away.
可以等警察来
As soon as they hear sirens, they scatter.
不能让他们跑了 他们一听到警笛就会散开
All right.
好吧
I'll draw their fire, you take them out.
我来吸引火力 你去干掉他们
- Negative. -  You can do this.
- 我拒绝 - 你能做到
- You're a great shot.
你射得很准
- But you're a slow runner.
但你跑得很慢
Fuck this.
去你的 糟了!
Get in!
上车!
So, you trust me now, or are you just desperate?
你现在相信我了 还是饥不择食了?
I saw you protect Angela and Mikey
我看见你保护安吉拉和米奇
so I guess you're playing it square.
所以我猜你说的是真的
You got a rat in your house, though, that's for sure.
但你那儿有内鬼 那是肯定的
Shit, Russo, it's the pedal on the right.
妈的 拉索 开快点
Let me do my job.
让我做我的工作
- Cut the corner. - There's a curb.
抄近路
- 有路缘石 - 跳过去
- Jump the curb! - Will you climb out of my ass?
你能别管我怎么开车吗?
I thought this was supposed to be a high-speed pursuit.
我以为这应该是高速追逐战
You're losing our best lead.
- 我们最好的线索要被你搞丢了
You want to drive?
- 你想来开车吗?
- Yes. - Hey, hey.
好啊
嘿!
You're a fucking menace, you know that?
- 你真他妈是个祸害!
You drive like you're blind.
- 你开车像个瞎子一样
Don't shoot. I'm done.
别开枪 我受够了
Okay? I'm done.
好吗?我受够了
You're under arrest, asshole.
- 你被捕了 混蛋
No.
- 不
These guys took a run at us in broad daylight at a crowded funeral.
这些人在光天化日之下 攻击我们 还是在人多的葬礼上
They're getting desperate.Means this thing's coming to a head fast.
他们越来越绝望了 这意味着这事快到紧要关头了
We take him in, he lawyers up
我们拘留他 他会请律师
and doesn't talk until it's too late
在为时已晚前缄口不言
and a terrorist has 650 chances
恐怖分子有650次机会
to take down a commercial airliner.
击落一架商业客机
So, what do you want me to do?
所以你想让我做什么?
Look the other way.
看向另一边
Oh, come on, man.
拜托 伙计
By not telling me everything you know
如果你不告诉我你知道的一切
you're protecting the people who killed my friends.
那就是在保护杀了我朋友的人
I'm not gonna waste my time
我不会浪费时间
with enhanced interrogation techniques.
用那些审讯技巧
I'm just gonna squeeze the life out of you.
我只会夺走你的生命
So, if at any point before you die
如果你在你死前
you feel like fully unburdening yourself...
想完全卸下自己的负担
blink.
那就眨眼
- Talk, now. - Okay.
- 现在说话 - 好的
Okay. Christ.
天啊
Let me catch my breath.
让我喘口气
We were supposed to use the gunfire
我们本来应该利用21响礼炮的枪声
from the 21-gun salute to mask our shot.
来掩盖我们的射击
Take you and your team down and get out of there
干掉你和你的团队成员
before anyone knew what was going on.
Easy payday for a couple professional hitters.
在任何人搞清楚状况前离开
对于专业枪手来说 赚这钱轻松容易
- Tell me something I don't know. - Like what?
- 跟我说些我不知道的事 - 比如?
Langston wouldn't give you all the cash up front.
兰斯顿不会一开始就把所有钱都给你
Where are you supposed to meet him to get the rest of the money?
你要在哪里见他拿尾款?
An abandoned building
皇后区某个破烂街区的
in some shitty neighborhood in Queens.
一栋废弃建筑里
Look, I-I can take you there.
我可以带你们去
But I don't know any Langston.
但我不认识兰斯顿
Then who hired you?
那是谁雇的你?
Some guy called Swan.
一个叫斯旺的家伙
- Copy that.
收到
Dixon and O'Donnell are in position.
迪克森和奥唐纳已就位
Russo's down the street.
拉索在街上
- All exits are covered. - Hear that?
所有出口都已覆盖 听到了吗?
You try anything, you'll be sorry.
你要是敢乱来 你会后悔的
But you go in there, get paid, give us the rundown...
你进去拿钱 给我们这地方的信息
How many inside, what they're packing...
里面有多少人 他们带着什么武器
Layout of the room, where everyone's sitting...
房间的布局 人都坐在哪里
We'll cut you loose and you get to keep the cash.
然后我们就放了你 你可以留着钱 懂了吗?
- Understood? - Yeah, man. Whatever.
好的 随便吧
I just never want to see you people again.
我只希望永远都不会再见到你们
Give me your phone.
把你的手机给我
Keep this in your pocket so we can listen in.
把这个放在口袋里 这样我们就能监听
You try anything, we come in hot
你要是敢做小动作 我们会突然进攻
and you die with the rest of them.
你就跟他们一起死吧
Get going, stupid.
去吧 蠢货
So, what are we thinking?
我们在想什么?
Swan went to work for New Age
斯旺去新时代工作
saw a chance to make the kind of money
看到了他一直梦寐以求的赚钱机会
he always dreamed of and took it?
然后就接受了?
Then what? He was hanging out with Franzy
然后呢?他跟弗朗茨一起出去玩
them being in the same city and all
他们都在一个城市
slipped and said something that made Franz suspicious?
不小心透露了什么 让弗朗茨产生了怀疑
Or...tried to get Franz in on it?
或者他试着拉弗朗茨入伙
Figured with a wife and kid, he'd need the money, too.
心想要养老婆和孩子 他也需要钱
Franz said no, tried to stop it
弗朗茨拒绝了 试图阻止
called Sanchez and Orozco for help.
打电话给 桑切斯和奥罗斯科求助
That sound about right?
那听起来对吗?
- I don't know
我不知道
but if Swan's really in that building
但如果斯旺真在那栋楼里
I'm gonna do the same thing I did to that guy.
我也会像对待那家伙一样对待斯旺
Wrap my hand around his neck and squeeze the truth out of him.
用手掐住他的脖子
- And after that?
在那之后呢?
Hello?
你好?
Anyone?
有人吗?
♪ Got to put it on the line ♪
♪ To make it stick ♪
♪ Got to tell them, baby ♪
♪ What makes you tick ♪
♪ It ain't no sin ♪
♪ To say what you want to say ♪
♪ But, baby, it's a sin ♪
♪ To stand in mercy's way ♪
- ♪ Do your thing, hey ♪ - ♪ Do your thing ♪
♪ Come on, don't stop ♪
♪ Don't you give up ♪
- ♪ Do your thing, hey ♪ - ♪ Do your thing ♪
♪ Come on, don't stop ♪
♪ Don't you give up ♪
♪ You got to do your thing ♪
♪ Do your thing ♪
- ♪ Do your thing ♪ - ♪ Do your thing ♪
♪ Uh, tough love ♪
♪ Ain't all to the good ♪
♪ Too many people ♪
♪ Are trampled underfoot ♪
♪ It ain't about ♪
♪ The skin you're in ♪
♪ But to know where you're going ♪
♪ You got to know where you've been ♪
- ♪ Do your thing, hey ♪ - ♪ Do your thing ♪
♪ Come on, don't stop ♪
♪ Don't you give up ♪
- ♪ Do your thing, hey ♪ - ♪ Do your thing ♪
♪ Come on, don't stop ♪
- ♪ Do your thing, yeah ♪ - ♪ Do your thing ♪
♪ Don't you give up, just ♪
- ♪ Don't you give up, baby ♪ - ♪ Do your thing ♪
- ♪ D-Don't you give up now ♪ - ♪ Do your thing ♪
- ♪ Just do your thing ♪ - ♪ Do your thing ♪
- ♪ D-Don't you stop, girl ♪ - ♪ Do your thing ♪
- ♪ Just do your thing, baby ♪ - ♪ Do your thing ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
- ♪ Do your thing ♪ - ♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Do your thing ♪